Edward E Griebel Jr.

edgriebel@gmail.com • 585-705-1093 • www.edgriebel.com github.com/edgriebel • linkedin.com/in/edgriebel

SUMMARY

Language-Agnostic Full Stack Developer with over 20 years of success creating software solutions. Wide breadth of experience in multiple industries, languages, tools, and third-party applications demonstrates success. Excited to create code to deliver high quality systems that support business growth.

Selected expertise: Java, Python, J2EE/JavaEE, MySQL, SQL, PL/SQL, JavaScript, JMS, RabbitMQ, Cognos, AppDynamics.

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Meta (Facebook)

August 2021 – Present

Production Engineer

- My team builds tools for full lifecycle automation of tens to thousands of physical servers or virtual machines by just editing a file.
- Selected projects: adding reliability and performance metrics including reporting to existing services; automating firmware updates across multiple hardware vendors.

Technologies: Python, SQL, Rust

At Meta, a Production Engineer applies software engineering techniques to achieve reliability, scalability, performance, and security goals.

Rochester Institute of Technology

August 2017 - Present

Adjunct Professor

- Currently teaching 3-credit undergraduate course in professional software engineering practices.
- Previous courses taught include undergraduate courses in Java and DBMS/SQL.

Marqeta Inc. May 2020 – July 2021

Lead Software Engineer

- Worked closely with peer developers, product owners, and operations teams to create a greenfield system
 to support a new credit card product including processing, accounting, statementing, and user-level APIs.
- Established/enhanced processes and procedures for product development and support.
- Mentored and guided other engineers with designs and general software engineering practices.

Technologies: Java, MySQL, Spring Boot, Docker, jOOQ

Logical Operations

Occasionally since January 2020

Consultant

Provided industry best practices and expertise for new courses in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, and Data Science.

Catalant Technologies

2019 - 2020

Principal Software Engineer

- Determined performance issues impacting Catalant's SaaS product stability/scalability and worked with technical managers, product owners, and engineering management for prioritization and resolution.
- Created, built consensus around, and implemented processes and procedures to improve developer productivity and long-term supportability of primary SaaS product.
- Mentored and guided junior developers in industry best practices and product platform.

Technologies: Python, Flask, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL, Docker, Elasticsearch

Paychex 2013 – 2019

Middleware Architect

- Created system in Python to rebalance 20,000 databases among 200 Azure cloud pools with algorithmic, statistical, and machine learning techniques using TensorFlow, Pandas, and scikit-learn.
- Built internal inventory system with web and REST APIs providing a single source of truth for virtualized and physical hosts, JVMs, CLRs, databases, and middleware. Relationships sourced from external management systems including AppDynamics, Puppet, ServiceNow, and Oracle.
- Created custom Chaos Monkey implementation that would randomly kill middleware appliances and Java processes daily in multiple environments.
- Implemented AppDynamics on over 20,000 JVMs to replace a custom built system that collected and

monitored JVM metrics, saving four FTEs annually.

Technologies: Java, JavaScript, Python, Oracle PL/SQL, Scikit-Learn, AppDynamics, Application Performance Monitoring (APM)

Axeda (division of PTC)

2010 - 2013

Senior Software Engineer

- Owned the integration, performance tuning, and upgrade of Cognos Business Intelligence module.
- Internal technical consultant for professional services and product management teams.

Paychex

• Lead team of five to create three public-facing fullstack Java/JavaScript applications. Created CI/CD deployment pipeline with Hudson. Mentored new developers and delivered technical training.

Frontier Communications

 Created Java applications to build DSL circuits and track sales commissions. Automated generation of Excel spreadsheets from Hyperion EssBase saving \$200,000 annually (two FTEs).

Global Crossing (division of Level3)

• Lead multi-site teams to create Java and Perl CGI telecom applications.

JP Morgan Chase

• Created trading systems in C/C++ and tactical applications for equity derivatives and HFT trading desks.

BlackRock Financial Management

■ Developed systems in C/C++ for MBS mortgage, Treasury, and Repo trading desks.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

M.S. in Computer Science

Expected Summer 2023

Bucknell University

B.S. in Computer Engineering

- Senior design project creating reference implementation of DHCP protocol for RFCs 1531 and 1534
- Concentrations in Digital Electronics and Geology

CERTIFICATIONS AppDynamics Certified Implementations Professional

November 2016

AWARDS

Paychex Paragon Award for Resiliency, Paychex

January 2019

Every year, five projects are chosen across Paychex that demonstrate resiliency, exceptional delivery, operational efficiency, etc. Our project, "Adaptive Load Balancing", was chosen. It routes requests in F5 BigIP GTM and LTMs across servers and data centers based on server load, real-time statistics, and other measures. Adaptive Load Balancing has reduced outages and improved response times for services using it.

AppDynamics Scale Award, AppDynamics

November 2015

Awarded by AppDynamics to the company that was able to quickly deploy the AppDynamics tool across the most complex environment. Our team deployed the AppDynamics tool to over 2,000 JBoss, WebLogic, and Windows IIS servers across production and non-production environments.

ACTIVITIES

Leader, Boy Scouts and Cub Scouts FAA Certified Private Pilot

2007 – Present

[Resume written in LAEX, created on 2022-06-08]